Guide to the Raquel Z. Rivera hip hop recordings, 1977-2005.
Rivera, Raquel Z. hip hop recordings
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Raquel Z. Rivera hip hop recordings, 1977-2005.
8066
Rivera
2 cubic feet.
Publications, Sound recordings, Video
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hip Hop CDs, Cassettes, and magazine issues relating to African-American hip hop, collected by Raquel Z. Rivera.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Raquel Z. Rivera is an author and singer-songwriter. She has a Ph.D. in Sociology and her areas of scholarly interest include popular music and culture, race and ethnicity, nation and diaspora, and the intersections between Latino and Africana studies. She is co-editor of the anthology Reggaeton (2009) and author of the book New York Ricans from the Hip Hop Zone (2003).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Hip Hop CDs, Cassettes, and magazine issues relating to African-American hip hop, collected by Raquel Z. Rivera.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rivera, Raquel Z.
Subjects:
Hip-hop.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Puerto Rican hip hop materials retained by the Archives of the Puerto Rican Diaspora, Centro de Estudios Puertorriqueños, Hunter College.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Audio CDs
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Audio Cassettes
Boxes 3-5
Series III. Video
Box 5
Series IV. Publications
Box 6
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Audio CDs
  - A Compilation Performed by: The 3rd Message, 2000; 1517 (Box 1)
  - Music From and Inspired by the Motion Picture 8 Mile Performed by: Various Artists, 2002; 1518 (Box 1)
  - Live at La Pena Performed by: Aya De Leon, 2002
  - Date of Birth Performed by: Arsonists, 2001; 1519 (Box 1)
  - Yeeeah Baby Performed by: Big Pun, 2000; 1520 (Box 1)
  - Behind the Front Performed by: Black Eyed Peas, 1998; 1521 (Box 1)
  - Non-Fiction Performed by: Black Sheep, 1994; 1522 (Box 1)
  - Double Consciousness Performed by: Blitz, 2005; 1523 (Box 1)
  - Heavy Rhyme Experience Performed by: The Brand New Heavies, 1992; 1524 (Box 1)
  - The Bytches Performed by: BWP, 1991; 1525 (Box 1)
  - Gimme Some More Performed by: Busta Rhymes, 1998; 1526 (Box 1)
  - Fresh Wild Fly Performed by: Cold Crush Brothers, 1995; 1527 (Box 1)
  - One Day it’ll all make sense Performed by: Common, 1997; 1528 (Box 1)
  - Fun Crusher Plus Performed by: Company Flow, 1997; 1529 (Box 1)
  - Black Sunday Performed by: Cypress Hill, 1993; 1530 (Box 1)
  - Jails Hospital & Hip-Hop Performed by: Danny Hoch, 1998; 1531 (Box 1)
  - Hobson’s Choice Performed by: Das Boot, 1532 (Box 1)
  - Vico-Para Raquel Performed by: Desahogo, 1533 (Box 1)
  - J.O.S.E. Performed by: Fat Joe, 2001; 1534 (Box 1)
  - Flat Linerz Performed by: FlatLinerz, 1994; 1535 (Box 1)
  - The Mix Tape Volume 3 Performed by: Funkmaster Flex, 1998; 1536 (Box 1)
  - Still Standing Performed by: Goodie Mob, 1998; 1537 (Box 1)
  - Diary of a madman Performed by: Gravediggaz, 1994; 1538 (Box 1)
  - Guru’s Jazzmatazz Performed by: Guru, 1993; 1539 (Box 1)
  - Revolutionary Vol 2 Performed by: Immortal Technique, 1540 (Box 1)
  - MidNight FreeStyle Performed by: In the House, 1541 (Box 1)
  - The New Reality Performed by: Jazzmatazz, 1995; 1542 (Box 1)
  - The sun rises in the east Performed by: Jeru the Damaja, 1994; 1543 (Box 1)
  - Toma De Posecion Performed by: Judiny, NA; 1544 (Box 1)
  - Late Registration Performed by: Kan Ye West, 1545 (Box 1)
  - Stand for Nothing Fall For Anything Performed by: Kodiak Brinks, 1546 (Box 1)
  - I Got Next Performed by: KRS-ONE, 1997; 1547 (Box 1)
  - The Last Poets Performed by: The Last Poets, 1548 (Box 1)
  - The Legend Performed by: The Legend, 1549 (Box 1)
  - Musical Deaho Performed by: Maria Isa, 1550 (Box 1)
  - The Blackout Performed by: Maspyke, 1999; 1551 (Box 1)
  - Paradisiaque Performed by: MC Solaar, 1997; 1552 (Box 1)
  - Bano De Luna Performed by: Melina Leon, 2000; 1553 (Box 2)
  - Merge Performed by: Merge, 1554 (Box 2)
  - Nadie Performed by: El Meswy, 1555 (Box 2)
  - NYC Everything Performed by: Method Man, 1556 (Box 2)
  - Black on Both Sides Performed by: Mos Def, 1999; 1557 (Box 2)
  - Black Star Performed by: Mos Def & Talib Kweli, 1558 (Box 2)
  - G-Strings Performed by: Mr. Green Weedz, 2005; 1559 (Box 2)
  - Noelia Performed by: Noelia, 1999; 1560 (Box 2)
  - N.O.R.E. Performed by: Noreaga, 1998; 1561 (Box 2)
  - Peeps Performed by: Peeps, 1998; 1562 (Box 2)
  - Labcabincalifornia Performed by: The Pharcyde, 1995; 1563 (Box 2)
  - A Sample of the world Performed by: Planet Rap, 1564 (Box 2)
  - Prime Under Ground 2 Performed by: Prime Under Ground 2, 1995; 1565 (Box 2)
  - Age of truth Performed by: Prophets of da City, 1566 (Box 2)
  - He Got Game Performed by: Public Enemy, 1998; 1567 (Box 2)
  - Elements I’m Among Performed by: Queen Latifah, 1996; 1568 (Box 2)
  - Man Behind the Music Performed by: Queen Pen, 1997; 1569 (Box 2)
  - The 18th Letter Performed by: Rakim, 1997; 1570 (Box 2)
  - Vol 1 Performed by: Rap Archives, 1996; 1571 (Box 2)
  - The Begining Performed by: Rappers, 1572 (Box 2)
  - Rasassination Performed by: Rass & Kass, 1998; 1573 (Box 2)
  - Dare iz a darkside Performed by: RedMan, 1994; 1574 (Box 2)
  - Phrenology Performed by: The Roots, 2002; 1575 (Box 2)
  - El Pro-Greso Performed by: SieteNueve, 1576 (Box 2)
  - Yes N Deed Performed by: Society, 1994; 1577 (Box 2)
  - No Mans Land Performed by: Souls of Mischief, 1995; 1578 (Box 2)
  - Shake whatcha Mama Gave Ya Performed by: Stik-E, 1995; 1579 (Box 2)
  - S.P.I.T. Performed by: Supernatural, 2005; 1580 (Box 2)
  - El Abayaued Performed by: Tego Calderon, 1581 (Box 2)
  - Atrevete Performed by: Tres Equis, 1582 (Box 2)
  - The Best of Reggae Dance Hall Vol1 Performed by: Various Artists, 1989; 1583 (Box 2)
  - Can’t stop won’t stop Performed by: Various Artists, 1584 (Box 2)
  - Soul in the Hole Performed by: Various Artists, 1585 (Box 2)
  - You Think You know Performed by: Various Artists, 1586 (Box 2)
  - Aquel que Habia Muerto Performed by: Vico C, 1998; 1587 (Box 2)
  - Project Blues Performed by: The Welfare Poets, 1588 (Box 2)
  - Rhymes for Treason Performed by: Welfare Poets, 1589 (Box 2)
  - Enter the Wu Tang Performed by: Wu Tang, 1993; 1590 (Box 2)
  - Wu Tang Forever Performed by: Wu Tang, 1591 (Box 2)
  - NA Performed by: NA, 1592 (Box 2)
- Series II. Audio Cassettes
  - The Cactus Album Performed by: 3rd Bass, 1989; tr-9024 (Box 3)
  - 8 Joints from Blunt Performed by: 8 Joints from Blunt, 1995; tr-9025 (Box 3)
  - As Nasty as they Wanna Be Performed by: 2 Live Crew, tr-9026 (Box 3)
  - Put it in your mouth Performed by: Akinyele, 1996; tr-9027 (Box 3)
  - Noise in the Attic Performed by: Arcenius Curtiss Bryant
  - Beats,Rhymes and Life Performed by: A Tribe Called Quest, 1996; tr-9028 (Box 3)
  - Bahamadia Kollage Performed by: Bahamadia, 1996; tr-9029 (Box 3)
  - Las Drogas Matan Performed by: Baron Lopez y D-Squad, 1989; tr-9030 (Box 3)
  - Fall 1995 to Summer 1996 Performed by: The Best of The E&J Show, tr-9031 (Box 3)
  - Sida Rap Performed by: Brewley M.C., 1989; tr-9032 (Box 3)
  - The Coming Performed by: Busta Rhymes, 1996; tr-9033 (Box 3)
  - Resurrection Performed by: Common Sense, 1994; tr-9034 (Box 3)
  - Ear to the Street Performed by: The Conscious Daughters, 1993; tr-9035 (Box 3)
  - Christmas Rap Music Performed by: Crew X, 1990; tr-9036 (Box 3)
  - Boogie Down Productions Performed by: Criminal Minded, 1994; tr-9037 (Box 3)
  - Unlabeled Performed by: Dance Hall, tr-9038 (Box 3)
  - Cocolos y roqueros Performed by: Das EFX, 1993; tr-9039 (Box 3)
  - Free At Last Extended Play Remix Performed by: DC Talt, tr-9040 (Box 3)
  - De La Soul is Dead Performed by: De La Soul, tr-9041 (Box 3)
  - Buddy & Ghetto Thang Performed by: De La Soul, 1989; tr-9042 (Box 3)
  - Unlabeled Performed by: Dead Prez, tr-9043 (Box 3)
  - Unlabeled Performed by: Dee Original Old School Flavor, tr-9059 (Box 3)
  - Digable Performed by: Digable, tr-9060 (Box 3)
  - The Platform Performed by: Dilated Peoples, 2000; tr-9061 (Box 3)
  - The Platform Performed by: Dilated Peoples, 2000; tr-9061 co.2 (Box 3)
  - Hypocrisy is the Greatest Luxary Performed by: The Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy, 1992; tr-9062 (Box 3)
  - Abusando Performed by: DJ Joe, tr-9063 (Box 3)
  - The New Testament Performed by: Doo Woop, tr-9064 (Box 3)
  - Straight outta Performed by: Edutainment, 1990; tr-9065 (Box 3)
  - Ill Na Na Performed by: Foxy Brown, 1996; tr-9066 (Box 3)
  - Brothas Doobie Performed by: Funkdoobiest, 1995; tr-9067 (Box 3)
  - The Mix Tape Performed by: Funkmaster Flex, 1995; tr-9068 (Box 3)
  - Blunted on Reality Performed by: Fugees (Tranzlator Crew), 1994; tr-9069 (Box 3)
  - ShadowBoxin’ 4th Chamber Performed by: Genius/GZA, 1995; tr-9070 (Box 3)
  - The Revolution will not be Televised Performed by: GI Scott Heron, 1988; tr-9071 (Box 3)
  - Soul Food Performed by: Goodie Mob, 1995; tr-9072 (Box 3)
  - Hip Hop Blend Performed by: Hip Hop Blend, tr-9073 (Box 3)
  - Amerikkka’s Most Wanted Performed by: Ice Cube, tr-9074 (Box 3)
  - Music from the Elektra Entertainment Group Performed by: Illstyle Live, 1995; tr-9075 (Box 4)
  - Reasonable Doubt Performed by: Jay-Z, 1996; tr-9076 (Box 4)
  - Wrath of the Math Performed by: Jeru The Damaja, 1996; tr-9077 (Box 4)
  - Facing You Performed by: Keith Jarrett, 1972
  - Blends of Heavy Mental Performed by: Killah Priest, 1997; tr-9078 (Box 4)
  - KRS-One Performed by: KRS-One, 1995; tr-9079 (Box 4)
  - Necessary Roughness Performed by: The Lady of Rage, 1997; tr-9080 (Box 4)
  - Asi Es La Vida Performed by: Latin Empire, 1990; tr-9081 (Box 4)
  - Hard Core Performed by: Lil Kim, 1996; tr-9082 (Box 4)
  - Real Ting Performed by: Mad Lion, 2006; tr-9083 (Box 4)
  - Eyes on This Performed by: MC Lyte, 1989; tr-9084 (Box 4)
  - Prose Combat Performed by: MC Solaar, tr-9085 (Box 4)
  - First Position Performed by: Mega Banton, tr-9086 (Box 4)
  - Urban Summer Sampler Performed by: Mercury, 1996; tr-9087 (Box 4)
  - I’ll be there for you Performed by: Method Man, 1995; tr-9088 (Box 4)
  - It’s Real Performed by: Mic Geronimo, 1994; tr-9089 (Box 4)
  - Naughty Performed by: Nagerel Brand Nubicon, tr-9090 (Box 4)
  - Naughty by Nature Performed by: Naughty by Nature, tr-9091 (Box 4)
  - L.I.F.E. Performed by: Nefertiti, 1994; tr-9092 (Box 4)
  - Volumen #2 Performed by: The Noise, tr-9093 (Box 4)
  - Lazy Afternoon Performed by: Nonchalant, 1994; tr-9094 (Box 4)
  - Lazy Afternoon Performed by: Nonchalant, 1994; tr-9094 co. 2 (Box 4)
  - Ol’ Dirty Bastard Performed by: Ol’ Dirty Bastard, tr-9095 (Box 4)
  - Stress Performed by: Organized Konfusion, 1994; tr-9096 (Box 4)
  - Aquemini Performed by: Outkast, 1998; tr-9097 (Box 4)
  - Guerrilla Funk Performed by: Paris, 1994; tr-9098 (Box 4)
  - Unlabeled Performed by: Party Tape Two, tr-9099 (Box 4)
  - Mecca and the soul Brother Performed by: Pete Rock, 1992; tr-9100 (Box 4)
  - Pete Rock Performed by: Pete Rock, tr-9101 (Box 4)
  - Bizzare Ride 2 the Pharcyde Performed by: The Pharcyde, 1992; tr-9102 (Box 4)
  - Fear of a Black Planet Performed by: Public Enemy, 1990; tr-9103 (Box 4)
  - No Way Out Performed by: Puff Daddy & The Family, 1997; tr-9104 (Box 4)
  - Hip Hop Inspired by the Black Panthers Performed by: Pump Ya Fist, 1995; tr-9105 (Box 4)
  - Questionable Contents Performed by: Questionable Contents, tr-9106 (Box 4)
  - All Hail the Queen Performed by: Queen Latifah, tr-9107 (Box 4)
  - Only Built 4 Cuban Linx Performed by: Raekwon, 1995; tr-9108 (Box 4)
  - Para tu Sauteb Performed by: Rap Cubano, tr-9109 (Box 5)
  - Rap Declares War Performed by: Rap Declares War, tr-9110 (Box 5)
  - Ras Kass Performed by: Ras Kass, tr-9111 (Box 5)
  - Muddy Waters Performed by: Red Man, 1996; tr-9112 (Box 5)
  - Tape 1 Performed by: Red Man, tr-9113 (Box 5)
  - Tape 2 Performed by: Red Man, tr-9114 (Box 5)
  - Unlabeled Performed by: Rise and Shine, tr-9115 (Box 5)
  - Do you want more? Performed by: The Roots, tr-9116 (Box 5)
  - Illadelph Halflife Performed by: The Roots, 1996; tr-9117 (Box 5)
  - Red, Hot & Cool Performed by: Sholem Moments, tr-9118 (Box 5)
  - You been Played Performed by: Smooth, tr-9119 (Box 5)
  - Children of the Corn Performed by: Soulsville, 1994; tr-9120 (Box 5)
  - Here We Come Performed by: Timbaland, 1998; tr-9121 (Box 5)
  - Players Performed by: Too Short, 1987; tr-9122 (Box 5)
  - TF Performed by: True Funkalistic, 1995; tr-9123 (Box 5)
  - Volumen 2 Performed by: U Records, tr-9124 (Box 5)
  - Select old School Hip Hop Performed by: Various Artists, tr-9125 (Box 5)
  - Hip Hop Scuaps Performed by: Various Artists, tr-9126 (Box 5)
  - Underground Records Performed by: Various Artists, tr-9127 (Box 5)
  - Zap MAMA Performed by: Zap MAMA, tr-9128 (Box 5)
- Series III. Video
  - The Show Produced by: Rysher Entertainment in association with Russell Simmons, 1996; V-5929 (Box 5)
    ISBN: 0-8001-8384-3
- Series IV. Publications
  - The Source Issue #: 99, December 1997 (Box 6)
  - VIBE, November 1995 (Box 6)
  - VIBE, September 1997 (Box 6)
  - VIBE, August 1997 (Box 6)
  - VIBE, May 1998 (Box 6)
  - VIBE, December/January 1998/1999 (Box 6)
  - Stress, Spring 1996
  - Stress, November 1995 (Box 6)
  - Stress Issue #: 7, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Stress Issue #: 11, February/March 1998 (Box 6)
  - Stress Issue #: 13, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Stress Issue #: 14, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Mosaic, Summer 2001
  - Mosaic, Spring 2002
  - Battle Sounds, 2 copies Volume #: 4, March 1996 (Box 6)